<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Compose All The Things</title><link>https://composeallthethings.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Compose All The Things</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://composeallthethings.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitoring a Raspberry Pi with Prometheus and Grafana</title><link>https://composeallthethings.com/monitoring-a-raspberry-pi-with-prometheus-and-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://composeallthethings.com/monitoring-a-raspberry-pi-with-prometheus-and-grafana/</guid><description>Deploying a Prometheus and Grafana Monitoring Setup with Docker Compose If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to monitor your Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s system performance, Prometheus and Grafana are a powerful duo that can help. And using Docker Compose makes setting up this monitoring system a breeze. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to set up this monitoring system step-by-step using Docker Compose.
The Components There are three main components to this monitoring setup:</description></item><item><title>Automating Postgres Deployment with Docker Compose and Init Scripts</title><link>https://composeallthethings.com/automating-postgres-deployment-with-docker-compose-and-init-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 19:20:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://composeallthethings.com/automating-postgres-deployment-with-docker-compose-and-init-scripts/</guid><description>Introduction to Running PostgreSQL in a Docker Container using Docker Compose In this blog post, we will explore how to run PostgreSQL in a Docker container using Docker Compose. We will also break down and explain the init-user-db.sh script that is executed at startup to initialize the PostgreSQL tables. Running PostgreSQL in a Docker container provides several benefits, including ease of deployment, portability, and isolation. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and understand the process!</description></item><item><title>A New Beginning - Let us explore!</title><link>https://composeallthethings.com/a-new-beginning-let-us-explore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 15:12:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://composeallthethings.com/a-new-beginning-let-us-explore/</guid><description>Welcome to my New Blog: # Welcome to my New Blog: Exploring Docker Compose, Orchestration, and Systems Development! Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to introduce you to my brand-new blog, a dedicated space where I&amp;rsquo;ll be showcasing all of my Docker Compose, Orchestration, and Systems Development projects. I created this blog because my previous one, exitcode0.net, was starting to get cluttered and lose focus. With this fresh start, I aim to provide you with valuable content and stay on topic.</description></item></channel></rss>